let question = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "Unresponsive victim is characterized by",
        options: [
            "Does not respond to any stimulus",
            "Respond to verbal stimuli",
            "Respond to painful stimuli",
            "Respond to pinching of the skin"
        ],
        answer: "Does not respond to any stimulus"
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "Vomiting of blood is known as",
        options: [
            "Hematemesis",
            "Melena",
            "Internal bleeding",
            "Epistaxis"
        ],
        answer: "Hematemesis"
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "The goal of the primary survey is to quickly assess",
        options: [
            "Bleeding, wounds",
            "Kidneys, cardiovascular, and nervous systems",
            "Respiratory, cardiovascular systems, and liver",
            "Respiratory, cardiovascular, and nervous systems"
        ],
        answer: "Respiratory, cardiovascular, and nervous systems"
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "Fever is a sign of wound infection",
        options: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        answer: "True"
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "What type of bleeding requires very little attention",
        options: [
            "arterial bleeding",
            "venous bleeding",
            "capillary bleeding",
            "hemorrhage"
        ],
        answer: "capillary bleeding"
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "The AVPU scale is used to determine",
        options: [
            "Degree of bleeding",
            "Type of fracture",
            "The victim history",
            "The victim's level of responsiveness"
        ],
        answer: "The victim's level of responsiveness"
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "What is the first step to stop bleeding from wounds in the extremities (hands/legs)",
        options: [
            "Put ice on the wound",
            "Apply direct pressure",
            "Elevate the extremities",
            "Bed rest"
        ],
        answer: "Apply direct pressure"
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "The first aider should check unresponsive victim's pulse by feeling",
        options: [
            "Popliteal artery",
            "Radial artery",
            "Carotid artery",
            "Temporal artery"
        ],
        answer: "Carotid artery"
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "In minor open wounds, such as abrasions, there is only a small amount of damage and minimal bleeding",
        options: [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        answer: "True"
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "Which of the following techniques the first aider should use to open the airway of an unconscious causality",
        options: [
            "Jaw thrust",
            "Chin tilt, head lift",
            "Head tilt and jaw thrust",
            "Head tilt and chin lift"
        ],
        answer: "Head tilt and chin lift"
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "Complications of bleeding include",
        options: [
            "Burn",
            "Organ failure",
            "Fracture",
            "Wound infection"
        ],
        answer: "Organ failure"
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "A person, who is an unconscious, with absent breathing and pulse needs",
        options: [
            "Back blows and chest thrusts",
            "Heimlich maneuver",
            "Rescue breathing",
            "CPR"
        ],
        answer: "CPR"
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "A wound that is usually resulting from accidental injury; there are pathogenic organisms and foreign bodies in the wound is known as",
        options: [
            "Infected",
            "Colonized",
            "Clean",
            "Contaminated"
        ],
        answer: "Contaminated"
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "Tetanus is a complication of",
        options: [
            "Shock",
            "Fracture",
            "Bleeding",
            "Wound"
        ],
        answer: "Wound"
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "A wound that has regular edge resembling a surgical cut and caused by sharp instrument such as knife or arbor is called",
        options: [
            "Contusion",
            "Incision",
            "Abrasion",
            "Puncture"
        ],
        answer: "Incision"
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "Responsive victim is breathing",
        options: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        answer: "True"
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "Hemorrhage refers to a large amount of bleeding in a short time",
        options: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        answer: "True"
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "How long should you check for breathing while performing CPR",
        options: [
            "seconds 30",
            "seconds 2",
            "seconds 10",
            "seconds 5"
        ],
        answer: "seconds 10"
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "Acute wounds take a longer time to heal, and may have complications",
        options: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        answer: "False"
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "Bleeding from nose is known as",
        options: [
            "Hematemesis",
            "Epistaxis",
            "Hemoptysis",
            "Melena"
        ],
        answer: "Epistaxis"
    },
    {
        numb: 21,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "Injury of the soft parts, hemorrhage and swelling is called",
        options: [
            "Incision",
            "Bleeding",
            "Fracture",
            "Contusion"
        ],
        answer: "Contusion"
    },
    {
        numb: 22,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "Once you begin CPR, do not stop except if the scene becomes unsafe",
        options: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        answer: "True"
    },
    {
        numb: 23,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "First aid should be done slowly and efficiently",
        options: [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        answer: "False"
    },
    {
        numb: 24,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "Which of the following is the correct ratio of chest compression to breaths during CPR (one first aider)",
        options: [
            "5 compressions: 1 rescue breath",
            "15 compressions: 2 rescue breaths",
            "2 compressions: 30 rescue breaths",
            "30 compressions: 2 rescue breaths"
        ],
        answer: "30 compressions: 2 rescue breaths"
    },
    {
        numb: 25,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "Venous bleeding is bright red, often rapid ooze",
        options: [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        answer: "False"
    },
    {
        numb: 26,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "All of the followings are open wounds except",
        options: [
            "Contusion",
            "An abrasion",
            "Laceration",
            "Punctures"
        ],
        answer: "Contusion"
    },
    {
        numb: 27,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "What should be your first concern at the scene of accident",
        options: [
            "Check the victims breathing and pulse",
            "Call your local emergency phone number",
            "Check the scene for safety",
            "Cool the burned area"
        ],
        answer: "Check the scene for safety"
    },
    {
        numb: 28,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "Internal bleeding occurs through a natural opening such as the vagina, mouth, nose, or anus, or through a break in the skin",
        options: [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        answer: "False"
    },
    {
        numb: 29,
        type: "True/False",
        question: "First aids is an emergency care and treatment of a sick or injured person before more advanced medical assistance arrives",
        options: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        answer: "True"
    },
    {
        numb: 30,
        type: "Multiple Choices",
        question: "What type of bleeding produces bright red blood spurts with each heartbeat",
        options: [
            "Capillary bleeding",
            "Hemorrhage",
            "Venous bleeding",
            "Arterial bleeding"
        ],
        answer: "Arterial bleeding"
    }
]